<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Tombleson Family Cookbook</title><link>https://cookbook.jamestombleson.com/</link><description>Recent content on Tombleson Family Cookbook</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Mon, 30 Jan 2023 00:00:00 -0700</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://cookbook.jamestombleson.com/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Spatchcock Smoked Turkey</title><link>https://cookbook.jamestombleson.com/recipes/2023/01/spam-musubi/</link><pubDate>Mon, 30 Jan 2023 00:00:00 -0700</pubDate><guid>https://cookbook.jamestombleson.com/recipes/2023/01/spam-musubi/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Homemade Chicken and Dumplings</title><link>https://cookbook.jamestombleson.com/recipes/2023/01/chicken-and-dumplings/</link><pubDate>Wed, 11 Jan 2023 06:36:00 -0700</pubDate><guid>https://cookbook.jamestombleson.com/recipes/2023/01/chicken-and-dumplings/</guid><description>Ingredients Base 1/2 cup (113 g) unsalted butter 1 yellow onion, finely chopped 3 carrots, cut into ½-inch dice 2 ribs celery, finely chopped 3 cloves garlic, finely minced 1/2 cup (60 g) all-purpose flour 5 cups (1200 ml) chicken broth 1/3 cup (80 ml) heavy cream 2 teaspoons kosher salt 1/2 teaspoon black pepper 1/2 teaspoon dried thyme 2 bay leaves 1 cup frozen peas 4 cups cooked chicken, diced small 3 tablespoons minced parsley For the Dumplings 2 cups (240 g) all-purpose flour 1 tablespoon baking powder 1 teaspoon salt 2 tablespoons unsalted butter, melted 1 cup (240 ml) milk Instructions Place the chicken stock in a small saucepan and warm over low heat.</description></item><item><title>Spatchcock Smoked Turkey</title><link>https://cookbook.jamestombleson.com/recipes/2022/10/spatchcock-smoked-turkey/</link><pubDate>Sun, 23 Oct 2022 00:00:00 -0700</pubDate><guid>https://cookbook.jamestombleson.com/recipes/2022/10/spatchcock-smoked-turkey/</guid><description>Ingredients 1 15-pound turkey (spatchcocked) 8 Tablespoons salted butter (softened) 4 Tablespoons olive oil 1 Tablespoon coarse kosher salt 1 Tablespoon coarse black pepper Instructions Preheat the smoker. Preheat your smoker to 275 degrees F with your favorite hardwood. I recommend pecan, maple, apple, or alder for smoking turkeys. On this turkey I tried almond wood for the first time and it was great! Spatchcock the turkey. Spatchcock your turkey by removing any giblets, neck, or other internal parts from your bird.</description></item><item><title>Pumpkin Chiffon Pie</title><link>https://cookbook.jamestombleson.com/recipes/2022/10/pumpkin-chiffon-pie/</link><pubDate>Fri, 21 Oct 2022 00:00:00 -0700</pubDate><guid>https://cookbook.jamestombleson.com/recipes/2022/10/pumpkin-chiffon-pie/</guid><description>Notes Makes one 9&amp;quot; deep-dish pie Ingredients Crust 12 graham crackers 2 Tbsp. sugar 1/4 tsp. kosher salt 6 Tbsp. unsalted butter, melted, slightly cooled Filling and Assembly 1 envelope unflavored gelatin (2½ tsp.) 1 tsp. ground cinnamon 1/4 tsp. ground nutmeg 3/4 (scant) cup plus 2 Tbsp. sugar, divided 3/4 tsp. kosher salt, divided 3 large egg yolks 3/4 cup whole milk 1 1/4cups unsweetened pumpkin purée (from one 15-oz.</description></item><item><title>Raspberry Streusel Bars</title><link>https://cookbook.jamestombleson.com/recipes/2022/10/raspberry-streusel-crumb-bars-recipe/</link><pubDate>Fri, 21 Oct 2022 00:00:00 -0700</pubDate><guid>https://cookbook.jamestombleson.com/recipes/2022/10/raspberry-streusel-crumb-bars-recipe/</guid><description>Ingredients 2 2/1 cups (312.5 g) all-purpose flour 2/3 cup (133.33 g) granulated sugar 1/2 teaspoon (0.5 teaspoon) salt 1 cup (227 g) plus 2 tablespoons unsalted butter, divided, cut into ½-inch pieces and at cool room temperature 1/4 cup (55 g) light brown sugar 1/2 cup (40.5 g) old-fashioned rolled oats 1/2 cup (49.5 g) pecans, chopped fine, (2 ounces ) 3/4 cup (255 g) raspberry preserves, (8½ ounces) 3/4 cup (90 g) fresh raspberries, (3½ ounces) 1 tablespoon lemon juice Instructions Preheat the oven to 375 degrees F.</description></item><item><title>Sweet Potato Casserole with Marshmallows &amp; Streusel</title><link>https://cookbook.jamestombleson.com/recipes/2022/10/sweet-potato-casserole-with-marshmallows-streusel/</link><pubDate>Fri, 21 Oct 2022 00:00:00 -0700</pubDate><guid>https://cookbook.jamestombleson.com/recipes/2022/10/sweet-potato-casserole-with-marshmallows-streusel/</guid><description>Ingredients 3 to 3 1/4 pounds sweet potatoes*, peeled and chopped into large chunks, see note 2 tablespoons unsalted butter 1/4 cup milk or half and half 1/2 teaspoon ground cinnamon or pumpkin pie spice 2 tablespoons brown sugar salt, to taste Instructions Mashed Sweet Potatoes 1.Preheat oven to 375°F. Grease a 2 or 2 ½ quart casserole dish (preferably a rectangle or oval so there&amp;rsquo;s a decent surface area for the topping; I use an 8×11) and set aside.</description></item><item><title>Crispy Smashed Potatoes</title><link>https://cookbook.jamestombleson.com/recipes/2022/10/crispy-smashed-potatoes/</link><pubDate>Fri, 07 Oct 2022 09:30:00 -0700</pubDate><guid>https://cookbook.jamestombleson.com/recipes/2022/10/crispy-smashed-potatoes/</guid><description>Ingredients 2 pounds baby Yukon gold potatoes 3 tablespoons olive oil 1/2 teaspoon salt 1/2 teaspoon freshly cracked black pepper 1/2 teaspoon garlic powder Instructions Place the potatoes in a large pot and fill it with cold water. Bring the water to a boil. Simmer the potatoes until they are just barely fork tender. Strain the potatoes and let them cool slightly.
Preheat the oven to 450 degrees F.
Brush a baking sheet with 1 1/2 tablespoons of olive oil.</description></item><item><title>Butter Pecan Shortbread &amp; Browned Butter Toffee Filling</title><link>https://cookbook.jamestombleson.com/recipes/2022/09/butter-pecan-shortbread-browned-butter-toffee-filling/</link><pubDate>Wed, 28 Sep 2022 06:36:00 -0700</pubDate><guid>https://cookbook.jamestombleson.com/recipes/2022/09/butter-pecan-shortbread-browned-butter-toffee-filling/</guid><description>Ingredients Shortbread 1 cup (2 sticks or 226 grams) unsalted butter, softened but still cool 1/2 cup confectioners’ sugar 2 1/4 cups all-purpose flour 1/4 teaspoon salt 1 cup chopped pecans (more or less, to taste) crushed toffee pieces (or Heath Bits o’ Brickle), for garnish
Filling 1/2 cup (1 stick or 113 grams) unsalted butter, browned and cooled to room temperature 2 cup confectioners’ sugar (unsifted) 1 tablespoon heavy cream 1/2 teaspoon vanilla extract pinch of salt 3/4 cup crushed toffee pieces (or Heath Bits o’ Brickle) Instructions Cookies To make the cookies: Preheat oven to 300 degrees.</description></item><item><title>Roasted Chicken Gyros with Tzatziki and Feta Fries</title><link>https://cookbook.jamestombleson.com/recipes/2022/09/chicken-gyros-with-feta-fries/</link><pubDate>Wed, 28 Sep 2022 06:36:00 -0700</pubDate><guid>https://cookbook.jamestombleson.com/recipes/2022/09/chicken-gyros-with-feta-fries/</guid><description>Ingredients Chicken 1/2 cup plain full-fat Greek yogurt 1/4 cup extra virgin olive oil 1/4 cup fresh lemon juice 5 garlic cloves, finely minced or grated 1 tablespoon smoked paprika 1 tablespoon chopped fresh oregano Kosher salt and black pepper 1 1/2 pounds boneless skinless chicken breasts 6 fresh pitas or naan bread, warmed Tzatziki, pickled onions, radish, and lettuce, for serving Feta Fries 1/4 cup extra virgin olive oil 2 garlic cloves, minced or grated 3 tablespoons chopped fresh oregano 1/2 to 1 teaspoon cayenne pepper Kosher salt and black pepper 4 medium russet potatoes, cut into 1/4-inch-thick matchsticks 1/2 cup crumbled feta cheese Instructions To make the chicken.</description></item><item><title>Sun-Dried Tomato Pasta with Chicken and Mozzarella</title><link>https://cookbook.jamestombleson.com/recipes/2022/09/chicken-mozzarella-pasta-with-sun-dried-tomatoes/</link><pubDate>Wed, 28 Sep 2022 06:36:00 -0700</pubDate><guid>https://cookbook.jamestombleson.com/recipes/2022/09/chicken-mozzarella-pasta-with-sun-dried-tomatoes/</guid><description>Ingredients sun-dried tomato sauce 3 garlic cloves 4 oz sun-dried tomatoes olive oil salt paprika basil 1 cup half-and-half (or ½ cup heavy cream + ½ cup milk) 1 cup Mozzarella cheese, shredded ¼ teaspoon red pepper flakes Instructions In a large skillet, on medium heat sauté garlic and sun-dried tomatoes in the olive oil. Remove the sun-dried tomatoes from the skillet when done. Season sliced chicken with salt and paprika.</description></item><item><title>Pasta e Fagioli Soup</title><link>https://cookbook.jamestombleson.com/recipes/2022/06/pasta-e-fagioli-soup/</link><pubDate>Tue, 28 Jun 2022 09:21:26 -0700</pubDate><guid>https://cookbook.jamestombleson.com/recipes/2022/06/pasta-e-fagioli-soup/</guid><description>Ingredients 1 tablespoon olive oil plus extra for drizzling 1 pound Italian sausage casings removed 3 carrots peeled and chopped 2 ribs celery chopped 1 onion chopped 4 garlic cloves minced ¼ teaspoon salt ½ teaspoon Italian seasoning 1 teaspoon dried oregano ¼ teaspoon crushed red pepper flakes 28 ounce can peeled tomatoes chopped, juice reserved Parmesan rind 15 ½ ounce can cannellini beans rinsed and drained 4 cups low-sodium chicken broth divided 1 cup water 6 ounces ditalini or other small pasta 2 cups sliced baby spinach leaves Salt and pepper to taste Chopped fresh parsley leaves for garnish 2 ounces grated Parmesan cheese for garnish Instructions Heat olive oil in a large Dutch oven over medium until shimmering.</description></item><item><title>Drop Biscuits</title><link>https://cookbook.jamestombleson.com/recipes/2022/06/drop-biscuits/</link><pubDate>Mon, 27 Jun 2022 14:17:21 -0700</pubDate><guid>https://cookbook.jamestombleson.com/recipes/2022/06/drop-biscuits/</guid><description>Ingredients 4 ounces cold unsalted butter (1 stick; 115g), cut into 1/4-inch pieces and refrigerated 1 1/2 cups all-purpose flour (8 ounces; 225g) 2 teaspoons baking powder 1 teaspoon (4g) Diamond Crystal kosher salt; for table salt use half as much by volume or the same weight 3/4 cup (180ml) whole milk Directions Preheat oven to 400°F (200°C) and line a baking sheet with parchment paper; alternatively, grease the baking sheet with butter.</description></item><item><title>Instant Pot Pinto Beans</title><link>https://cookbook.jamestombleson.com/recipes/2022/06/instant-pot-pinto-beans/</link><pubDate>Mon, 27 Jun 2022 14:12:49 -0700</pubDate><guid>https://cookbook.jamestombleson.com/recipes/2022/06/instant-pot-pinto-beans/</guid><description>Ingredients 1 pound dry pinto beans 5 1/2 cups water 1 2/3 Tablespoon Better Than Bullion vegetable base salt and pepper to taste (Honestly, mine didn&amp;rsquo;t need any. The BTB flavored them perfectly. Taste them first.) Instructions Rinse off your pinto beans, and drain them using a wire mesh strainer. Add them to the Instant Pot, along with the water and Better Than Bullion vegetable base. Close and lock the lid, and cook on manual high pressure for 45 minutes.</description></item><item><title>Japanese Chicken Curry</title><link>https://cookbook.jamestombleson.com/recipes/2022/06/japanese-curry/</link><pubDate>Mon, 27 Jun 2022 12:59:10 -0700</pubDate><guid>https://cookbook.jamestombleson.com/recipes/2022/06/japanese-curry/</guid><description>Ingredients 1 1/2 lb boneless, skinless chicken thighs (beef, pork, seafood, tofu, mushrooms, or more vegetables; you can increase up to 2 lbs/907 g) kosher/sea salt (I use Diamond Crystal; use half for table salt) freshly ground black pepper 2 carrots 2 onions 1-2 russet potatoes (2-3 yukon gold potatoes if you want to preserve the potato shape) 1/2 Tbsp ginger (grated) 2 cloves garlic 1 1/2 Tbsp neutral-flavored oil (vegetable, rice bran, canola, etc) 4 cups chicken stock/broth (if you&amp;rsquo;re careful with sodium intake, you can use water only, or use half stock + half water) 1 apple (I used fuji apple; use as much as you like to add sweetness) 1 Tbsp honey 1/2 tsp kosher/sea salt (I use Diamond Crystal; use half for table salt) 1 package Japanese curry roux (7-8 oz or 200-230 g; or use all of my homemade curry roux) 1 1/2 Tbsp soy sauce 1 Tbsp ketchup Instructions Prep Discard the extra fat from the chicken and cut it into bite size pieces.</description></item><item><title>Chicken Tikka Masala</title><link>https://cookbook.jamestombleson.com/recipes/2022/06/chicken-tikka-masala/</link><pubDate>Mon, 27 Jun 2022 11:30:26 -0700</pubDate><guid>https://cookbook.jamestombleson.com/recipes/2022/06/chicken-tikka-masala/</guid><description>Ingredients Makes 6 servings
6 garlic cloves, finely grated 4 tsp. finely grated peeled ginger 4 tsp. ground turmeric 2 tsp. garam masala 2 tsp. ground coriander 2 tsp. ground cumin 1 1/2 cups whole-milk yogurt (not Greek) 1 Tbsp. kosher salt 2 lb. skinless, boneless chicken breasts, halved lengthwise 3 Tbsp. ghee (clarified butter) or vegetable oil 1 small onion, thinly sliced 1/4 cup tomato paste 6 cardamom pods, crushed 2 dried chiles de árbol or ½ tsp.</description></item></channel></rss>