<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Main on Tombleson Family Cookbook</title><link>https://cookbook.jamestombleson.com/course/main/</link><description>Recent content in Main on Tombleson Family Cookbook</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Mon, 30 Jan 2023 00:00:00 -0700</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://cookbook.jamestombleson.com/course/main/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Spatchcock Smoked Turkey</title><link>https://cookbook.jamestombleson.com/recipes/2023/01/spam-musubi/</link><pubDate>Mon, 30 Jan 2023 00:00:00 -0700</pubDate><guid>https://cookbook.jamestombleson.com/recipes/2023/01/spam-musubi/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Spatchcock Smoked Turkey</title><link>https://cookbook.jamestombleson.com/recipes/2022/10/spatchcock-smoked-turkey/</link><pubDate>Sun, 23 Oct 2022 00:00:00 -0700</pubDate><guid>https://cookbook.jamestombleson.com/recipes/2022/10/spatchcock-smoked-turkey/</guid><description>Ingredients 1 15-pound turkey (spatchcocked) 8 Tablespoons salted butter (softened) 4 Tablespoons olive oil 1 Tablespoon coarse kosher salt 1 Tablespoon coarse black pepper Instructions Preheat the smoker. Preheat your smoker to 275 degrees F with your favorite hardwood. I recommend pecan, maple, apple, or alder for smoking turkeys. On this turkey I tried almond wood for the first time and it was great! Spatchcock the turkey. Spatchcock your turkey by removing any giblets, neck, or other internal parts from your bird.</description></item><item><title>Roasted Chicken Gyros with Tzatziki and Feta Fries</title><link>https://cookbook.jamestombleson.com/recipes/2022/09/chicken-gyros-with-feta-fries/</link><pubDate>Wed, 28 Sep 2022 06:36:00 -0700</pubDate><guid>https://cookbook.jamestombleson.com/recipes/2022/09/chicken-gyros-with-feta-fries/</guid><description>Ingredients Chicken 1/2 cup plain full-fat Greek yogurt 1/4 cup extra virgin olive oil 1/4 cup fresh lemon juice 5 garlic cloves, finely minced or grated 1 tablespoon smoked paprika 1 tablespoon chopped fresh oregano Kosher salt and black pepper 1 1/2 pounds boneless skinless chicken breasts 6 fresh pitas or naan bread, warmed Tzatziki, pickled onions, radish, and lettuce, for serving Feta Fries 1/4 cup extra virgin olive oil 2 garlic cloves, minced or grated 3 tablespoons chopped fresh oregano 1/2 to 1 teaspoon cayenne pepper Kosher salt and black pepper 4 medium russet potatoes, cut into 1/4-inch-thick matchsticks 1/2 cup crumbled feta cheese Instructions To make the chicken.</description></item><item><title>Sun-Dried Tomato Pasta with Chicken and Mozzarella</title><link>https://cookbook.jamestombleson.com/recipes/2022/09/chicken-mozzarella-pasta-with-sun-dried-tomatoes/</link><pubDate>Wed, 28 Sep 2022 06:36:00 -0700</pubDate><guid>https://cookbook.jamestombleson.com/recipes/2022/09/chicken-mozzarella-pasta-with-sun-dried-tomatoes/</guid><description>Ingredients sun-dried tomato sauce 3 garlic cloves 4 oz sun-dried tomatoes olive oil salt paprika basil 1 cup half-and-half (or ½ cup heavy cream + ½ cup milk) 1 cup Mozzarella cheese, shredded ¼ teaspoon red pepper flakes Instructions In a large skillet, on medium heat sauté garlic and sun-dried tomatoes in the olive oil. Remove the sun-dried tomatoes from the skillet when done. Season sliced chicken with salt and paprika.</description></item><item><title>Japanese Chicken Curry</title><link>https://cookbook.jamestombleson.com/recipes/2022/06/japanese-curry/</link><pubDate>Mon, 27 Jun 2022 12:59:10 -0700</pubDate><guid>https://cookbook.jamestombleson.com/recipes/2022/06/japanese-curry/</guid><description>Ingredients 1 1/2 lb boneless, skinless chicken thighs (beef, pork, seafood, tofu, mushrooms, or more vegetables; you can increase up to 2 lbs/907 g) kosher/sea salt (I use Diamond Crystal; use half for table salt) freshly ground black pepper 2 carrots 2 onions 1-2 russet potatoes (2-3 yukon gold potatoes if you want to preserve the potato shape) 1/2 Tbsp ginger (grated) 2 cloves garlic 1 1/2 Tbsp neutral-flavored oil (vegetable, rice bran, canola, etc) 4 cups chicken stock/broth (if you&amp;rsquo;re careful with sodium intake, you can use water only, or use half stock + half water) 1 apple (I used fuji apple; use as much as you like to add sweetness) 1 Tbsp honey 1/2 tsp kosher/sea salt (I use Diamond Crystal; use half for table salt) 1 package Japanese curry roux (7-8 oz or 200-230 g; or use all of my homemade curry roux) 1 1/2 Tbsp soy sauce 1 Tbsp ketchup Instructions Prep Discard the extra fat from the chicken and cut it into bite size pieces.</description></item><item><title>Chicken Tikka Masala</title><link>https://cookbook.jamestombleson.com/recipes/2022/06/chicken-tikka-masala/</link><pubDate>Mon, 27 Jun 2022 11:30:26 -0700</pubDate><guid>https://cookbook.jamestombleson.com/recipes/2022/06/chicken-tikka-masala/</guid><description>Ingredients Makes 6 servings
6 garlic cloves, finely grated 4 tsp. finely grated peeled ginger 4 tsp. ground turmeric 2 tsp. garam masala 2 tsp. ground coriander 2 tsp. ground cumin 1 1/2 cups whole-milk yogurt (not Greek) 1 Tbsp. kosher salt 2 lb. skinless, boneless chicken breasts, halved lengthwise 3 Tbsp. ghee (clarified butter) or vegetable oil 1 small onion, thinly sliced 1/4 cup tomato paste 6 cardamom pods, crushed 2 dried chiles de árbol or ½ tsp.</description></item></channel></rss>