<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Italian on Tombleson Family Cookbook</title><link>https://cookbook.jamestombleson.com/cuisine/italian/</link><description>Recent content in Italian on Tombleson Family Cookbook</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Wed, 28 Sep 2022 06:36:00 -0700</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://cookbook.jamestombleson.com/cuisine/italian/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Sun-Dried Tomato Pasta with Chicken and Mozzarella</title><link>https://cookbook.jamestombleson.com/recipes/2022/09/chicken-mozzarella-pasta-with-sun-dried-tomatoes/</link><pubDate>Wed, 28 Sep 2022 06:36:00 -0700</pubDate><guid>https://cookbook.jamestombleson.com/recipes/2022/09/chicken-mozzarella-pasta-with-sun-dried-tomatoes/</guid><description>Ingredients sun-dried tomato sauce 3 garlic cloves 4 oz sun-dried tomatoes olive oil salt paprika basil 1 cup half-and-half (or ½ cup heavy cream + ½ cup milk) 1 cup Mozzarella cheese, shredded ¼ teaspoon red pepper flakes Instructions In a large skillet, on medium heat sauté garlic and sun-dried tomatoes in the olive oil. Remove the sun-dried tomatoes from the skillet when done. Season sliced chicken with salt and paprika.</description></item><item><title>Pasta e Fagioli Soup</title><link>https://cookbook.jamestombleson.com/recipes/2022/06/pasta-e-fagioli-soup/</link><pubDate>Tue, 28 Jun 2022 09:21:26 -0700</pubDate><guid>https://cookbook.jamestombleson.com/recipes/2022/06/pasta-e-fagioli-soup/</guid><description>Ingredients 1 tablespoon olive oil plus extra for drizzling 1 pound Italian sausage casings removed 3 carrots peeled and chopped 2 ribs celery chopped 1 onion chopped 4 garlic cloves minced ¼ teaspoon salt ½ teaspoon Italian seasoning 1 teaspoon dried oregano ¼ teaspoon crushed red pepper flakes 28 ounce can peeled tomatoes chopped, juice reserved Parmesan rind 15 ½ ounce can cannellini beans rinsed and drained 4 cups low-sodium chicken broth divided 1 cup water 6 ounces ditalini or other small pasta 2 cups sliced baby spinach leaves Salt and pepper to taste Chopped fresh parsley leaves for garnish 2 ounces grated Parmesan cheese for garnish Instructions Heat olive oil in a large Dutch oven over medium until shimmering.</description></item></channel></rss>